<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>

<image>
	<url>https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-cropped-PF-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>wearePF</title>
	<link>https://wearepf.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 

		<item>
		<title><![CDATA[It’s time to unpack the stuffy accountant stereotype. Do you still believe in it?]]></title>
		<link>https://wearepf.com/stuffy-accountant/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 11:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[erin@wearepf.com]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wearepf.com/?p=16363</guid>
		<description>A description here</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/819803749?h=2be1f7a0dd" width="640" height="464" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe>

As a senior content writer who writes exclusively for accountants, I spend hours with our clients mapping out engaging content. It’s in these conversations they regularly share they're often concerned about what people think of their career. More specifically, the fact they’re an accountant must mean they’re dull, boring individuals.

A quick Google brings up a plethora of firms who want to make it clear they're not monotonous, conversation-dry, human calculators. They’ll go to great lengths to clarify to any prospect they’re everything but the “typical, stuffy accountant”. Ultimately, the word stuffy boils down to being seen as boring.

At PF, we know the stereotype exists for a reason but it sure as heck doesn’t apply to the accountants we work with. However, we <em>have</em> learned when a client mentions they’re “not stuffy,” it’s often because deep down <strong>they believe they actually are</strong>.

As marketing experts, this presents us with an interesting conundrum. We’re regularly given a list of “we are nots” by accountants and it’s our job to reflect that list back to them through visual design and creative content.

The trouble is, when you have a perception of yourself even <em>you’re</em> not aware of, it can really muddy the waters. You have thoughts of what an accountant <em>should</em> be, often resulting in believing you can't fully show yourself through your brand. Sure, you want to prove you’re not stuffy, but you might still have the hang-up you’re “just” an accountant.

It’s that reductive thinking that will prevent you from fully embracing a brand you’ll love (and, by extension, prospects and clients will love too). It’s crucial to align who you are with how you show up in your marketing and brand because when you communicate authenticity, it appeals to the people you want to attract. When you attract <em>those</em> people, it invariably leads to more business.

Authenticity sells.
<h2>The accounting industry has been cracked open by innovation.</h2>
Whether you’re a traditional accountant or carving out your own path, we all work completely differently these days. It’s 99% less paperwork, all digital and 24/7 communication (depending on your preference). Nowadays, an accounting life is fast paced, varied and sometimes highly pressurised. The technological wave has altered a largely rhythmic, pattern-based accounting industry into one that can change from day-to-day.

The way you do your work is intuitive, cloud-based and instant (with a steady stream of finance tools and apps always around the corner). There’s a wealth of daily information available to clients meaning they’re involved in their finances in a way they never were before. They’re asking questions, raising concerns, and hiring in strategic advice. The very clients themselves are varied, hyper-involved and often have multiple revenue streams.

Today's accountants are straddling a really interesting moment in time for the industry. You don’t need to keep receipts, you don’t have neat stacks of paper on a desk. The “stuffy” accountant just doesn’t make sense in this new context because you don’t <em>need</em> to work that way anymore.

Given you’re experiencing a tech revolution first-hand, it wouldn’t be a surprise to find out you’re functioning well in this new world while unknowingly holding onto ties from the last.
<h2>There’s nothing wrong with labels if they correctly describe who you are and what you do.</h2>
There’s absolutely no problem if you’re thinking: ”I like old-school, that’s who I am!”. Stuffy is not synonymous with “traditional”.

There’s a strong market for traditional accounting, and if you’re a traditional accountant with a business that aligns with who you are and what you want to achieve, you’re good to go. It means your brand is authentic and your ideal client will be drawn to you because you are who you say you are. There won’t be a conflict and ultimately you’ll appeal to your prospects.

However,<strong> it is an issue</strong> if you say you do things <strong>differently</strong> but knowingly or unknowingly <strong>emulate</strong> traditional accounting methods and behaviours.

<strong>It’s also an issue</strong> if you say you’re <strong>traditional</strong> but knowingly or unknowingly <strong>defer</strong> from traditional accounting methods and behaviours.

Both are just as problematic as each other and here’s why.
<h2>A disorientated brand shakes the trust between you and your prospects.</h2>
Going out of your way to avoid associations with the word “stuffy” can result in you making brand decisions you’re not fully behind and that quickly becomes a problem when a prospect interacts with your business. It goes both ways, whether you’re conservative or alternative.

For example, if you’re actually quite conservative but you don’t want to be labelled as “boring” you might<strong> choose colours, images and social platforms that don’t fit your brand</strong>.

This type of disoriented brand might look like:
<ul>
 	<li>Having a TikTok account but lacking the enthusiasm or knowledge to know what to post</li>
 	<li>Electing for bright brand colours that clash with the voice you use in your content and communications</li>
 	<li>Adopting an edgy tone of voice you wouldn’t necessarily use yourself</li>
</ul>
Equally, if you’re not a traditionalist but you think you need to “look and sound like an accountant” to be taken seriously, you might still <strong>choose colours, images and social platforms that don’t fit your brand</strong>.

This type of disoriented brand could look like:
<ul>
 	<li>Sending formally worded emails that don’t feel or sound natural to you</li>
 	<li>Choosing typically “financial” colours (like blue or green) for your brand without thinking what you really want</li>
 	<li>Even wearing a suit to every meeting</li>
</ul>
Now, it doesn’t just boil down to two types of misdirection when it comes to branding, but the impact of the types of decisions you make and how you make them are the same across the board.

<strong>When your brand decisions are subliminal reactions, rather than proactive choices, it causes one major, long-term issue</strong>. It attracts prospects you don’t connect with and sends away the ones you would.

Let’s defer to your “consumer mind” for a second. When you visit a website that doesn’t look, sound or feel like you: what do you do?

You click away. You don’t feel a connection. You forget about them.

That’s what happens with a disorientated brand. It alters the synergy between themselves and the customer. When they get it wrong, it’s powerful. It can be an instant deal breaker or worse: send them to someone they <em>will</em> connect with.

When you get that synergy right, and your brand shows up for a prospect or client in the way they were expecting (and need) it will completely transform your business.
<h2>Here’s some indicators your own preconceptions are tripping up your brand.</h2>
These small things will tell you if how you market your brand and how you show up are aligned.

<strong>Your emails</strong>
Do you write more formally than you speak? Not to be confused with being respectful, if you write differently to how you interact with clients on the phone, it’s worth checking if you’re putting on an accounting jacket that doesn’t really fit.

<strong>Your tone of voice</strong>
In all of your content, from your website, through to your social posts, through to your emails. Does the voice of your content authentically align with how you communicate - across the board?

<strong>Instant aversions to design and tone of voice</strong>
This is a good temperature check. If you’ve outsourced design or content in the past, and the results have made you uncomfortable, ask yourself why. Of course, your personal taste might come into this, but if you found yourself saying “that’s too much” or “I can’t speak like that” - ask yourself why.

<strong>Preconceived notions of how to look or act</strong>
Do you ever find yourself saying: “I can’t do <em>that</em>” but you want to? Think tattoos, swearing, sharing social posts, sharing opinions on social media, different working hours, sharing personal information or wearing certain clothes. Of course this is dependent on what you feel comfortable with, but if you have a preconceived notion that an accountant needs to be a certain way, it’s definitely worth lassoing that thought and investigating why.
<h2>Being yourself isn’t unprofessional.</h2>
Jonathan, the founder of <a href="https://raedan.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Raedan</a> and a PF client, realised if he wanted his business to thrive, he’d have to “unlearn” accounting behaviours he’d unquestionably adopted in training.

At some point early in his career, he’d learned to write to a client like he was writing a letter to the editor of the Times. No matter what his colleagues were like to their clients in person, they just would not communicate the same way in their written communication.

Fast forward to when he had his own accounting business, he realised if he wanted to appeal to his type of client, artists and all-out creatives, he wasn’t going to gain their business if he spoke this way.

Then a lightbulb moment. He had a choice. He could drop the act (and it worked).

It turns out using contractions is normal. Speaking like the queen? Less so.
<h2>Stop telling the world what you’re not. Start telling people what <em>you are</em>.</h2>
Now, let’s talk about the popular line: “not your typical accountant”. As a senior content writer, I try to avoid using it at all costs for a few reasons.
<ul>
 	<li>It’s used a million times over. Rather ironically, it’s turning into a bit of a cliche! There are way more interesting parts to who you are and what you do. Tell your audience about <em>those</em> bits.</li>
 	<li>Never punch down. Just because you might not be traditional, doesn’t mean you need to throw shade on someone in the same industry.</li>
 	<li>It perpetuates the stereotype for the industry, it doesn’t dispel it. Know the phrase, “thou doth protest too much”? Yep, that!</li>
</ul>
Telling the world what you’re not instead of what you are, is <em>way</em> less impactful. Sure, you could be “not stuffy” or you could be, “quick-thinking techy humans who are great with numbers”. However you market your brand, it tells a prospect who you are and what you care about.

If you’re spending valuable content space telling them everything you’re not, you’re dramatically reducing the opportunity to tell them all the positive things you are. It’s a “show, don’t tell” situation. If you’re not stuffy, show how unstuffy you are through all of your choices.
<h2><em>You</em> define what an accountant is. It’s not the other way around.</h2>
In holding back on your humanness and the defining, unique qualities that make you attractive to your ideal audience, you’re tying one hand behind your back and robbing yourself of the opportunity for connection with a prospect.

If you’re an accountant, and you’re also really into heavy metal, <strong>you’re still an accountant</strong>. That doesn’t change and that’s a good thing. Mentioning it on your social media or in conversation with a client humanises you. Crucially it’s not getting overly familiar or “cutesy” with a client, it’s just showing them you’re a person too.

Humanising isn’t about getting a prospect or client to like you by revealing private information. It's about building a line of trust, honesty and connection between you and your clients. The sooner you do that, the longer they’ll stay, the more people they’ll tell about you and the work they trust you with will keep coming. Also, it’s important to say,<em> you’re</em> in control of what you let them know. But, let them know something about you because they’ll almost certainly return the favour.

When your brand represents who you really are, and what you really think, it reinforces the relationship between you and your client. <strong>It won’t threaten it</strong>. Good marketing divides, and playing it safe won’t win you any favours. It just turns away the clients you’d like to see more of.

We’re all different. And your clients love you for it.
<h2>Have the courage to run the firm you want, your way.</h2>
Our clients are great examples of what an accountant looks like nowadays. They’re a generation of professionals driven by purpose, intent on using their business to bring about change (for themselves, their family or their community). They’re app-using, connected accountants operating in every single corner of every single industry, a lot of them remotely. They’re all very different from one another but ultimately want the same thing: to proudly own a business as authentic as they are and help their clients do the same thing.

They’re sharp, strategic experts who prefer to make proper human connections with their type of people, whatever that looks like to them. They’re into getting the right imagery and colours and utilising powerful wording. They’ve learned they can choose who they work with, and often have refined, niche channels of clients who depend on them wholeheartedly. <strong>They really care about how they market themselves</strong>.

A discord between brand and owner puts a wedge between you, your clients and prospects. If you act one way but appear another through your brand, you <em>will</em> attract the wrong clients. You send away the ones who would actually love to work with you. Most importantly you’ll be dissuading ideal clients who would otherwise cultivate a powerful, positive energy within you to keep doing what you’re doing.
<h2>The pressure of being someone you’re not melts away when you embrace the type of accountant you really are.</h2>
Internally battling a stereotype is an unwinnable fight because you’re really just fighting yourself. Better to grab the bull by the horns and learn what type of accountant you really are and show that through your business.

Totally traditional? Great, communicate and reflect that in your brand and whew, things feel a lot easier. Prefer to do things differently? Fabulous - we love to see it!

Whoever you are, just make sure you tell the whole damn world.
<h2>Pssst….</h2>
<h3>Matching our clients with a brand that truly reflects them is what we do.</h3>
Reflecting clients fully within their brand is our jam. We do it through meaningful, structured processes that really dig into what you care about. Some of our clients call it marketing therapy.

If this article struck a particular chord with you, there’s some services you’ll want to hear more about. Ask us about a <a href="https://wearepf.com/branding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">brand project</a>, <a href="https://wearepf.com/diagnostic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tone of voice session</a> or <a href="https://wearepf.com/diagnostic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">naming workshop</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>16363</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2023-04-21 11:11:52]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2023-04-21 11:11:52]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2023-04-21 11:11:52]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2023-04-21 11:11:52]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[stuffy-accountant]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accountancy-firm"><![CDATA[accountancy firm]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accountancy-firm-marketing"><![CDATA[accountancy firm marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accountant"><![CDATA[accountant]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accountants"><![CDATA[accountants]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="all"><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="branding-identity"><![CDATA[branding identity]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="content"><![CDATA[Content]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="marketing-emails"><![CDATA[marketing emails]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="marketing-for-accountants"><![CDATA[marketing for accountants]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="pf-marketing-tips"><![CDATA[PF Marketing Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="plans-strategy"><![CDATA[Plans &amp; Strategy]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="social-media-for-accountants"><![CDATA[social media for accountants]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tone-of-voice"><![CDATA[tone of voice]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[32]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[add_custom_body_class]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dfiFeatured]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[500]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[60]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_estimated-reading-time-minutes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_wordproof_timestamp]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[stuffy accountant]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[You know you don't fit the stuffy accountant stereotype and you want to authentically show this in your brand and marketing.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[65]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[16365]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[When marketing meets operations: an accountancy firm love story]]></title>
		<link>https://wearepf.com/marketing-meets-operations/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 10:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alice Butler]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wearepf.com/?p=16380</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/824039968?h=a076f1a73a" width="640" height="464" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>

<em>Once upon a time, a marketing strategist and an operations lead were working in an accountancy firm.  These two people represented divisions which were very different from one another, and yet they shared a common goal: to make the company profitable. Marketing was like a proud peacock, always strutting around and attracting attention with its colourful feathers. Operations, who we will refer to as ‘Ops’, was more like an ox, strong and dependable, providing the foundation for everything the company did. Due to their differences the two departments often worked independently of one another and had challenges in achieving the results they wanted for the firm. Then one day a chance meeting changed everything…</em>

I’m going to tell you a love story about these two people. As you read, you’ll have a better understanding of:

<strong>1. The importance of having a marketing strategy:</strong> What are your marketing goals? How are you going to get leads? How can you ensure these leads are your ideal clients?

<strong>2. How aligning your marketing and operational strategies enables you to meet your business goals with more ease!</strong>

<strong>3. The encouragement that it is not difficult to align these strategies:</strong> Through data, goal setting and forward planning you can serve clients more effectively and your business can grow in line with your goals… I promise!

You’re already aware of the value an operations role delivers for your firm, in paying attention to efficiencies and profitability. And I suspect you're aware how marketing can bring  in the type of clients you love to work with, and who you’re able to do your best work for.

What you now need to consider, and implement, is how to bring your operations and marketing activity <strong>together</strong>. As you read this love story, you’re going to learn about the powerful impact this will have on your firm, and how to go about making the match!

All marketing starts with considering your audience, so before we get into the why’s and how’s, let’s first look at the attributes you’d want from successful operations and marketing divisions. All good love stories these days start with an awkward dating profile, so not to disappoint…
<p style="text-align: center;">Marketing Director , Age 29</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>“Hi there! I'm marketing, and I'm all about creativity, innovation, and making connections. I love coming up with new ideas and finding ways to promote things that people are passionate about. Whether it's a new product, a new service, or a new idea, I'm always up for a challenge…”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Creative- strategic-communicative-adaptable-passionate</strong></p>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16381" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/date-mockup-2v2.png" alt="" width="1200" height="884" />
<p style="text-align: center;">Operations Director , Age 35</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>"Hi! I'm the operations manager you didn't know you needed in your life. I love solving problems, optimising processes, and making everything run like a well-oiled machine. When I'm not busy keeping the world spinning, you can find me enjoying a good cup of coffee and binge-watching my favourite TV shows. Looking for someone who's ready to join my team and take on the world together!"</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>detail-oriented - problem solver- strong communicator- organised- team player</strong></p>
You might not be at a stage with your firm where you are ready to employ both an operations and marketing lead. Aligning your marketing and operations activity will still be valuable to you even if it’s one person who’s wearing all the hats. This is less about bringing people together, and more about integrating functions in your firm so they’re all working towards the same end goal.

When aligning these two leads, we recommend you start with data, a language they both need to be able to speak and an area that, when aligned, can have an exceptional impact on your accountancy firm.
<h2>The first date: data</h2>
<em>One day the finance department was sitting staring at an excel spreadsheet; he analysed marketing's data figures and separately pondered operations figures. Suddenly, BRAINWAVE! He realised if they could have each other’s numbers this could be magic! . He slammed his laptop shut and set about playing matchmaker for the two of them….”</em>

You recognise the value in using data to drive decisions. You wouldn’t prepare next year’s financial forecast for a client without looking at their previous years numbers. The same goes for bringing together your operations and marketing activity. The first place you can look to combine their strategies is using  data.

<strong>1. Collaborate on your data analysis:</strong> When operations and marketing join forces to collaborate on data analysis they can use actual numbers to set achievable goals that serve clients and the rest of the team.  For example, operations is responsible for calculating your team capacity for each quarter (i.e. the amount of work your team can get done based on the current size of team and skills you have).  You’ll be able to identify how many clients you need in order to reach full capacity. This number can then get translated into sales and marketing goals, and your marketing strategy will focus on how to reach these goals.

<strong>2. Make time for relationship management:</strong> Marketing, is in part, responsible for delighting clients- ensuring they get the services they need and delivered to the highest standard! As marketing shares data on customer interactions and feedback, they can identify areas where improvements can be made and develop strategies to enhance the overall customer experience. For example, some qualitative data collection, such as collecting NPS scores, could be carried out and reveal that clients would like a quicker turn-around time on work. Ops can work with the team to improve the efficiency of work, uncover bottle necks and ensure processes are in place to ease workloads. Marketing can ensure clients are clear on our processes and promises to deliver high quality work and why it may take the time it does.

<strong>3. Track your performance:</strong> Aligned target setting and performance tracking has been the most powerful way for us to see results here at PF. Devoid of collaboration, marketing may work on their target of ‘ signing three leads a week’, and operations may work on ‘getting 200 billable hours completed a week’.  Whereas, when the targets are set collaboratively, ops is able to inform marketing of their targets, which may sound a little like this:
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Operations: “Hey, to reach our financial target I need to give the team 200 hours of work this week”</em></p>
and Marketing, with clear knowledge of their conversion rates, could know “Hey to get you that much work, I must sign 5 leads a week”.

If you do not set targets and track performance collaboratively you are at risk of over-promising and under delivering to  clients, having a pressured workforce and not meeting annual targets.

The most effective way to use data collaboratively is to communicate, use data to set out targets, capabilities and review but most importantly talk about the data to ensure that Operations can deliver on the promises that Marketing makes.
<h2>Love is blind</h2>
<em>“Before long, Marketing and Ops realised that they were falling in love. From that day forward, the two worked closely together on every project. They collaborated on ideas, shared feedback, and worked tirelessly to produce the best possible results. They knew by working together, they could achieve greatness and take their company to new heights. Their collaboration was felt across the whole business.”</em>

It is easy to remain in the dark of just how great collaborative working on projects can be! Most recently, here at PF, our marketing and ops lead (yes, you guessed it, I am ops!) got together to embark on a full review of our services. Historically, our marketing director would have gathered client feedback and would have set about making any changes to client services inline with the feedback. However, working in alignment, we were able to collect and analyse data on profitability, pricing, processes, team feedback and client feedback.

To start the project we set about collecting historical data, operations collecting the following data on each service:

1. Number sold in the year prior

2. % completed within budget

3. Amount billable to client

4. Hours ( and cost of hours) spent on service

Marketing then collected the following information on each service:

5. Market research- how did our services compare to the market?

6. Stage in the buyer cycle

7. What clients does it help the most?

8. What does success for the clients look like?

9. What does success for us look like?

10. What are the challenges and opportunities?

Additionally, we assigned a divisional leads to obtain feedback on the services from the client facing team. The client facing team answered a series of questions about the services they delivered; including what they needed training on, what they felt clients got most value from and timeframes for delivery.

Together, we carried out client service review interviews and collated the data, making actionable conclusions on each service. This year we have set about making positive changes to improve our services based on this review!

Having shared goals from the outset meant for a thorough review with tangible outcomes which made sense across all divisions. One of the results of the service review was a decision to make a significant change to our website offerings. Actioning any change in a business can be daunting but knowing the correct research has gone into it and everyone is on the same page, and supporting the change, has made implementation so much easier.

We highly recommend getting your operations and marketing leads to align on a project, like a service review,  for you to see the benefits for yourself!
<h2>Operation’s proposal to marketing</h2>
<em>“I'm proposing that we work together more closely than ever before. Let's collaborate on every project, share feedback and insights, and ensure that our operational capabilities are aligned with your marketing strategies. Together, we can achieve amazing things and take our company to new heights. So, will you accept my proposal? Will you be my partner in this great adventure?"</em>

Once you have established these two roles within your accountancy firm, this professional relationship needs to be nurtured.  The following has worked for us at PF to encourage these roles to work successfully together:

<strong>Foster a culture of collaboration:</strong> Actively encourage collaboration between the operations and marketing departments by advocating for a culture of openness and cooperation in your accountancy firm. You can do this by sharing the company’s values, communicating your expectation for collaboration through team meetings, model it in the leadership time, regularly share company goals and encourage socialising amongst your team! This will help build trust and allow for open and honest feedback; if marketing wants to run a campaign that operations believes there is no capacity for, they can discuss this openly and productively.

<strong>Define common goals:</strong> The two  departments need to work together to define common goals that align with the overall business strategy. For example, when operations wants to improve the amount of time the team is spending on billable work, marketing can ensure that internal marketing  work is at a manageable level, and can support communicating this to the team in a positive way to get them on board.

<strong>Improve communication:</strong> Establish regular meetings between the operations and marketing departments to share information and ideas. This will help to ensure that everyone is on the same page and can work together effectively.

<strong>Implement shared metrics:</strong> Develop shared metrics that are relevant to both the operations and marketing departments. This will help align the efforts of both departments and provide a common language for measuring success. Setting clear financial targets such as revenue goals to both parties, and encouraging them to collaborate will result in operations improving efficiencies in line  with marketing plans. For example, you might decide a marketing event with the purpose of securing new leads is in the best interests of both parties, due to the shared revenue metric. Operations can support the planning, capacity planning and efficiency of the event and ensure client work is not impacted.

Agreeing to work alongside the four points above (being collaborative, setting common goals, communicating effectively and utilising metrics) is the foundation for exceptional service delivery! I recommend the collaboration between operations and marketing becomes a permanent feature in your business.   I say this because I often see accountancy firms with awesome systems, all over everything operational but only getting ad hoc marketing services. You may have set a marketing strategy at the start of the year and not returned or reviewed it alongside operations.

The best collaboration is not one-off, or here and there: it is consistent. Therefore we recommend a longer term plan for operations and marketing to work together; an agreement for a long standing working relationship. To get started on connecting the two, start with your company goals, look closely at the targets that marketing and ops both influence, and encourage them to set about on working on an aligned plan to reach the target.
<h2>The Vows</h2>
<em>“I promise to always communicate openly with you, to share my ideas and strategies, and to listen to your feedback and insights. I promise to be flexible and adaptable, working with you to ensure that our marketing plans are aligned with what you can deliver in operations”</em>
<h2>Profitability ever after</h2>
To summarise (and for those of you who skipped to the end ) here are the KEY BENEFITS &amp; ACTIONS to take in order to align your Operations and Marketing leads in an accountancy firm:

<strong>BENEFIT: Improved leadership:</strong> Establishing clear lead roles in marketing and operations ensures you have someone to lead, and collaborate, on the two agendas.
<ul>
 	<li><strong>ACTION</strong>: Assign an operations &amp; marketing lead today! Please <a href="https://wearepf.com/diagnostic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">complete the PF diagnostic</a> if you are considering outsourcing a marketing lead in your accountancy firm.</li>
</ul>
<strong>BENEFIT: Improved alignment:</strong> By working together, the operations and marketing leads can ensure that their efforts are aligned with the overall business strategy and goals.
<ul>
 	<li><strong>ACTION:</strong> Set business goals, share them with both leaders and give them the space to work on the goals together!</li>
</ul>
<strong>BENEFIT: Better client experience:</strong> When operations and marketing work together, they can create a more seamless and cohesive client experience. This can include everything from consistent branding and messaging to efficient processes that make it easy for clients to work with the firm.
<ul>
 	<li><strong>ACTION:</strong> See the client experience as the responsibility of both marketing and operations. Organise for the two of them to meet and analyse client feedback; what can they both do to improve the client experience?</li>
</ul>
<strong>BENEFIT: More effective marketing:</strong> By working closely with operations, the marketing team can gain a better understanding of the firm's strengths and capabilities, as well as the needs and preferences of clients. This can help to create more targeted and effective marketing campaigns that resonate with clients and drive business growth.
<ul>
 	<li><strong>ACTION:</strong> Invite operations into weekly marketing conversations. This may seem counterintuitive as they usually think and work differently, but the two perspectives will excel your marketing efforts and results!</li>
</ul>
<strong>BENEFIT: Improved efficiency:</strong> When operations and marketing work together, they can identify areas where processes can be streamlined or automated, leading to greater efficiency and productivity.
<ul>
 	<li><strong>ACTION:</strong> Invite marketing into weekly operations conversations! What services do clients want to see improved? What operations successes can we share with clients? What new processes do we need to teach to our team?</li>
</ul>
Bringing operations and marketing together can help to create a more integrated and effective accountancy firm that is better able to serve its clients, more proactive than reactive, and ultimately is able to reach its goals in a more efficient way!
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>“Operations and marketing lived happily ever after helping their company to become more competitive, innovative, and client-focused ensuring goals were met and profitability prevailed!”</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>16380</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2023-05-05 10:41:27]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2023-05-05 10:41:27]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2023-05-05 10:41:27]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2023-05-05 10:41:27]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[marketing-meets-operations]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accountancy-firm"><![CDATA[accountancy firm]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accountancy-firm-marketing"><![CDATA[accountancy firm marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="all"><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="marketing-strategy"><![CDATA[marketing strategy]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="pf-marketing-tips"><![CDATA[PF Marketing Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="plans-strategy"><![CDATA[Plans &amp; Strategy]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[32]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[add_custom_body_class]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dfiFeatured]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[500]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_estimated-reading-time-minutes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_wordproof_timestamp]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[16382]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_opengraph-image]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Marketing-Article-date-story-mockup-1024x573.png]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_opengraph-image-id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[16382]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[marketing and operations]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[When marketing meets operations: a love story %%page%% %%sep%% %%sitename%%]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[A story about how aligning your marketing and operations strategies enables you to meet your business goals.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[70]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[April 2023: Turning celebrations into quality content]]></title>
		<link>https://wearepf.com/april-2023-pf-marketing/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 09:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[profitablefirm]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wearepf.com/?p=16387</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[April's PF marketing update brings the accounting world season of awards. It’s been brilliant to see some of our clients among those being recognised, here you'll find some help on how to share your amazing achievement in your marketing!

We too have had some celebrations at PF over the last few months, with three of our team members being promoted into new roles and excitement over our first in-person event of the year. WOOP!

<img class="alignnone wp-image-16388 size-full" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/unnamed-6.png" alt="PF marketing" width="1199" height="435" />
<h2>Sharing your success in your marketing</h2>
Congratulations to all the incredible individuals who have won awards over the past month, including a few of you reading this! It was incredible to see one of our clients Georgi (co-owner of <a href="https://www.starfishaccounting.co.uk/?inf_contact_key=2672d3cbf9f268f1dadf3f2273a4af51d18a532c4142cb79caf2b269de1401fa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Starfish Accounting</a>) win Xero’s MVP award. An incredible recognition for the inspiring work Georgi does for the industry.

If there’s one thing we know about working with accountants, it’s that you can be too humble sometimes. You and your team spend every day helping your clients to do big things in their businesses and lives and yet, it can be hard to show this sometimes.

Winning an award is a perfect opportunity for you to share recognition of your work, without feeling like you’re simply “showing off”. You have a lot of supporters who love having the opportunity to celebrate you and your success: team members, clients, strategic partners, other accountants and bookkeepers.

<strong>Here’s a few ways you can talk about your award in your marketing:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li><strong>Share what the award means to you, personally.</strong> Use this as an opportunity to show more of your human side in your content. The focus is less on “this confirms I’m great at what I do” and more “this recognition encourages me to keep pushing the boundaries and making positive changes in my industry.”</li>
 	<li><strong>Congratulate other winners.</strong> This likely feels a lot more comfortable than talking about yourself! Tag other winners in social posts, or send them a private message congratulating them on their win.</li>
 	<li><strong>Write a blog post.</strong> What was the entry process like? What did you focus on in your entry submission? What motivated you to enter in the first place? Tell the story of your experience and share it on your website and in social posts.</li>
 	<li><strong>Record a video.</strong> You could record some video on the actual awards night and stitch together a short round up and/or you can record a video with your thoughts about the award and what it means for your firm and clients.</li>
</ul>
These are just some ideas to get you started and you can read more in our <a href="https://wearepf.com/won-an-award/?inf_contact_key=24fa36f65868f9e6785ec2eaec5c4290b7af0999dac2af6212784c39e05d2aef" target="_blank" rel="noopener">‘We’ve won an award. How do we shout about it without showing off?’</a> blog post!

And if you have won an award recently, let us know and we’d love to share your success with the world!

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-15361" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/PF_long_email_banners_New.png" alt="" width="1199" height="435" />
<h2>Kick Start Content Guide</h2>
As a content marketing agency, we live and breathe content on a daily basis. And yet, we recognise this isn’t the case for you as accountants, who are instead focused on the important work you do for your clients day after day.

That’s why we’ve created the <strong>Kick Start Guide!</strong> It’s your detailed list of the content you as an accountant or bookkeeper most need to create based on:
<ol>
 	<li>The categories of content your prospects most WANT</li>
 	<li>The content most accountants are missing</li>
</ol>
<h2>This guide is for every accountant and bookkeeper who:</h2>
<ul>
 	<li>Has a lot of marketing actions you’d like to work on, and <strong>aren’t sure what the highest priority is</strong></li>
 	<li><strong>Gets distracted by all your ideas</strong> and struggle to finish good content</li>
 	<li>Has <strong>clients who need more services</strong> from you but aren’t buying those yet</li>
 	<li>Finds yourself <strong>repeating the same content</strong> over and over again</li>
</ul>
You can use this guide to <strong>understand what content is valuable to create first</strong>, and get help actually creating it.

The guide is FREE for all PF Lab members and clients, or if you’re not yet either, you can pay £99+VAT for your copy of this 53-page guide! You also have the option to bolt-on accountability coaching calls with one of our team and they'll help you to make the most progress and get as much out of the guide as you can.

<a href="https://wearepf.com/kick-start-content-guide/?inf_contact_key=1dc59faf6dc8045cb3af8e90d515d3647e470d92b8b75168d98a0b8cac0e9c09" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Here’s the form to download your guide!</strong></a>

<em>If you’re a PF client or Lab member, <a href="mailto:team@wearepf.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">drop us an email</a> and ask us for the coupon code for your free copy!</em>

<img class="alignnone wp-image-16312 size-full" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/unnamed-7.png" alt="PF marketing" width="1199" height="435" />

<strong>Erin promoted to Senior Content Writer!</strong>

Since joining our team as a writer, Erin has impressed both us and our clients with her incredible skills and creativity. Her favourite thing about being a content writer is finding the best and most impactful words and using them to send the right message. Well done Erin!

<img class="wp-image-15670 size-medium aligncenter" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Erin-1-300x300.png" alt="team member" width="300" height="300" />

<strong>Amy promoted to Client Marketing Manager!</strong>

It’s been a joy to watch Amy grow into the Client Marketing Manager role in the 2 years she’s been at PF. The care she shows for her clients, combined with her creativity helps Amy thrive when collaborating with our clients to help them to reach their potential. Keep up the amazing work, Amy.

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16261 size-medium" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/pf-Amy-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" />

<strong>Chryzia promoted to Head of Design!</strong>

As one of our longest standing PF team members, Chryzia has seen PF and our clients through many different seasons of change. As the design team has grown, Chryzia has stepped up as the leader and is now officially our Head of Design! We're so excited to see her bring her creativity and innovative ideas to her new role.

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-15414 size-medium" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Chryzia-2-300x300.png" alt="team member" width="300" height="300" />

If you’ve got a promotion within your team to celebrate, or a new person has recently started with you, celebrate and share the exciting news in your content!

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-15362" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/PF_long_email_banners_Events.png" alt="" width="1199" height="434" />
<div>
<h2>PF Lab LIVE on 7 June in Central London</h2>
We’re really excited to be running our second PF Lab LIVE event and this time it’s going to be in Central London on 7th June 2023! This half-day event gives you an opportunity to step outside your normal working space, meet other accountants, work through ideas and get help from multiple PF team members.

<strong>The theme of the event is ‘Using storytelling in your marketing’ and most specifically how it helps:</strong>
<ol>
 	<li>To simplify your message</li>
 	<li>Speed up your buyers buying decision</li>
</ol>
There’ll be a variety of sessions throughout the day including breakouts, action sessions and an opportunity to learn from our Senior Content Writer, Erin and Marketing Director, Steph.

<strong>If you’re in the PF Lab or are a PF client, then this event is free for you to attend</strong>. Just <a href="mailto:team@wearepf.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">send us an email</a> saying “Yes to Lab Live”!

If you’re not yet a client or Lab member, you can join us for the event for a small fee of £99+VAT and <a href="https://wearepf.com/signup-one-off-training-session/?inf_contact_key=fd0c063c4f3444064278d98947189ad316358d5485884e2f31e6019a0d26c8b0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here’s the form to book your space!</a>

Venue details and final timings coming soon!

&nbsp;

That's everything from us for this month! If there's a question we haven't answered yet, or you're not sure where to find it, just <a href="mailto:team@wearepf.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">let us know</a> and we'll look after you. And keep up the really great work.

<em>If you'd like to receive this monthly round up, and other free PF resources each month, <a href="https://wearepf.com/free-resources/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up here</a>!</em>

</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>16387</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2023-05-08 09:55:37]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2023-05-08 09:55:37]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2023-05-10 15:32:04]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2023-05-10 15:32:04]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[april-2023-pf-marketing]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accountancy-firm"><![CDATA[accountancy firm]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accountants"><![CDATA[accountants]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accounting-event"><![CDATA[accounting event]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="all"><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="awards"><![CDATA[awards]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="blogging"><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="events"><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="live-events"><![CDATA[live events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="pf-lab"><![CDATA[PF Lab]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="pf-marketing-tips"><![CDATA[PF Marketing Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="recommendations"><![CDATA[Recommendations]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="team"><![CDATA[Team]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="team-updates"><![CDATA[team updates]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[35]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[add_custom_body_class]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dfiFeatured]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_estimated-reading-time-minutes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_wordproof_timestamp]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[16390]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[PF marketing]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[PF Marketing Update | April 2023 %%page%% %%sep%% %%sitename%%]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[In this PF marketing update, we share how to share your achievements in your marketing and details of our upcoming live event!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[72]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[How can I repurpose my existing content to get the most value out of it?]]></title>
		<link>https://wearepf.com/repurpose-content-get-most-value/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 09:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pfstephirving]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wearepf.com/?p=16407</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/827760043?h=e33c4760f2" width="640" height="564" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>

As a business owner running an accounting firm, your time is valuable. You want to spend it in the best way for your clients, your team and yourself.

One way to maximise your time is to create marketing content which reaches and educates more of the clients you do your best work for and love to partner with.

Given the time and energy investment required to create original, high quality content, you want to get the most value possible out of each piece of content you create.

To do this, <strong>you can repurpose your existing content and share it in lots of different formats</strong>. This is called <strong>stackable content</strong>.

As well as saving yourself a lot of content creation time, repurposing and expanding on content you’ve already created will:
<ul>
 	<li>Help your audience to learn in different ways: by reading, watching, listening</li>
 	<li>Make your content more digestible without losing the power of your message</li>
 	<li>Get your team involved in marketing: gives them the opportunity to use different skills sets i.e. writing, designing, creating video content</li>
</ul>
<h2>Types of stackable content you can create from written content</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16409" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/blog-flow-chartv2.png" alt="" width="1563" height="1042" />

<strong>A visual explainer:</strong> create a visual to share the key messages you want to get across, quickly. You can do this yourself with a tool like <a href="https://www.canva.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Canva</a> or <a href="https://wearepf.com/credits-request/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">request a quote</a> from a PF designer. High quality visuals can have the power to tap into the fears and concerns of your audience and show quickly and clearly how your firm can help them, while helping the viewer to process and retain the information.

Below is an example our design team created for Raedan. This trifecta illustrates how success in business is achieved by bringing together your accountant, your app stack and yourself. The message is visual, clear and connects with their ideal audience of creatives.

<img class="wp-image-16410 aligncenter" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Raedan-trifecta-1.png" alt="" width="870" height="871" />

<strong>Tutorial video:</strong> turn your “step by step” written instructions into videos to SHOW the process. You can use software like <a href="https://www.loom.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Loom</a> to record your screen and walk through the steps. Here’s an example taken from the original blog post: <a href="https://wearepf.com/how-to-write-great-marketing-email/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">how to write a great marketing email: 12 tips for writing clear and actionable email content</a>.

<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/774671383?h=af25d79dee" width="640" height="564" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>

<strong>Highlights video:</strong> what’s the ONE thing you want someone to learn from your blog post? Highlight your one thing in a short video to quickly get the message across in a clear and concise way. Here’s an example from Fork CPAs who address the commonly asked question: “How much should restaurant owners be paid?”.
<blockquote class="instagram-media" style="background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Cq_wTRsgfOW/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14">
<div style="padding: 16px;">

&nbsp;
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;"></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style="color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style="width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>
&nbsp;
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;"><a style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Cq_wTRsgfOW/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A post shared by The Fork CPAs (@forkcpas)</a></p>

</div></blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<strong>Longer-form video:</strong> this is for the more detailed and complex topics that require more explanation. These videos will often take longer to prepare for and record. You’ll want to consider how you might add these to your website alongside the original written content.

<strong>Repurpose the content in an email:</strong> resharing content you’ve already written is a powerful way to remind clients and prospects of your experience and value. Here’s some ways you can do this:
<ul>
 	<li><strong>Monthly newsletter:</strong> include an extract of your most helpful blog post from the month before and include a link for your audience to read the full version.</li>
 	<li><strong>Helpful email:</strong> if you’re sharing an update on a legislation change or a software update that affects your audience, include content you’ve already written on the topic. It’ll save you time not having to rewrite on the same topic, and it shows you’ve got experience in their particular industry or type of business.</li>
</ul>
<strong>A series of social posts:</strong> this is your space to share punchy and powerful chunks of content. You may already be familiar with how time consuming social media posts can be to draft so save yourself A LOT of effort and reuse content from blog posts you’ve already written.
<ul>
 	<li><strong>Share a post every time you write a new blog</strong>: pick out the top 1 or 2 key points from your blog and share them across your platforms (more detail on how to do this below!)</li>
 	<li><strong>Re-share your most relevant content</strong>: When you’ve created content which addresses the most commonly asked questions clients and prospects come to you with, you’ll want to reshare these posts time and time again so you can keep getting in front of more people you can help. The same goes for seasons within your client’s industries - if you know there’s a particular time of the year that specific content is helpful, re-share it year after year and get as much use out of it as you can.</li>
 	<li>For example, we know awards season comes around for accountants at the same time each year, so you’ll often see us sharing helpful content (like “<a href="https://wearepf.com/won-an-award/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">how do we shout about our award without showing off?</a>”) around that time. And remember, if you need to update some of the details of the blog post, do so. For transparency you can add a line saying “this blog post has been edited in line with 2023 policy changes” and you’ll be good to go!</li>
</ul>
<h2>Types of content you can create from webinar or seminar recordings</h2>
<img class="alignnone wp-image-16411 size-full" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/webnar-flow-chartv2.png" alt="repurpose existing content" width="1563" height="1042" />

<strong>A blog post:</strong> use a tool like <a href="https://www.happyscribe.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HappyScribe</a> to get a transcription of the recording, and use the content to write a blog post. You will need to make some adjustments so it reads well as a written piece of content (rather than literally spoken word written down) but you’ll be starting off with sentences you can build from and repurpose.

<strong>Use transcript for emails:</strong> similar to including portions of your blog posts or PDF guides in your emails, you can do the same with your webinar transcripts. Pick out specific messages from the recording to reuse as written email content for both prospects and clients.

<strong>Create shorter videos:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li><strong>For your website:</strong> having 1-hour long webinar recordings on your website isn’t the most dynamic or engaging way to share key messages from the session. Instead, record time stamps of the highlight sections, cut up the video (using a video editing tool) and stitch together clips using a tool like <a href="https://www.canva.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Canva</a>. You’ll have a shorter, more powerful video that gets the point across quickly while still giving value.</li>
 	<li><strong>For your social posts:</strong> clip out portions of your webinar recording and create a series of short video clips to share on your social media platforms.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Create stackable content for each of your social media platforms</h2>
<img class="alignnone wp-image-16412 size-full" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/social-posts-flow-chartv2.png" alt="repurpose existing content" width="1563" height="1042" />

Social media is one of the best places to share your stackable content and it helps considerably when it comes to planning your social media calendar. Instead of coming up with new content for every post, make use of what you already have and repurpose it for the platforms you know your audience spends time on. <a href="https://wearepf.com/guide-posting-different-social-media-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Use this guide for ideas of what content to post on each platform!</a>

<strong>LinkedIn:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Create a series of posts and include 1-2 key messages in each one. You don’t need to spend time introducing the topic, as that’s what the introduction of your long-form content does. Get to the point quickly and show the reader the value straight away. Include a link in the comments to take them to the full blog post, webinar recording or video.</li>
 	<li>Tag any clients, team members and strategic partners who are either relevant to the message, or who you feel would benefit from seeing it.</li>
</ul>
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/stephanie-coward_why-is-brand-so-important-for-accountants-activity-7059474191846162433-d4AB?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Here’s a LinkedIn post</a> repurposing the key messages from this <a href="https://wearepf.com/visual-guide-branding-important-accountants/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">visual guide to why branding is important for accountants</a>.

<strong>Twitter:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>What’s the ONE message you want your audience to learn from reading your piece of content? Make that your twitter post and include a link for them to read the full version.</li>
</ul>
<strong>Instagram stories:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>You’ve got 90 seconds to give value to your followers. Pick out the key messages from your written and video content and share them as a series on your stories. Instagram stories disappear after 24 hours so post videos you’d like followers to be able to see again and again as a reel instead.</li>
</ul>
<strong>Instagram reels:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Remember those short clips you cut out of your webinar or seminar recording? You want to be clipping these together as a reel on Instagram. Add captions to your video so it can be played on mute. Write a post caption to reinforce the core message and encourage people to watch your video!</li>
</ul>
<strong>Instagram grid posts:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>The most visual of your stackable content is best posted here, on your Instagram grid. You can create short, punchy statements to grab people’s attention as they’re scrolling through their feed. Share a link to the full content in the post caption. <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CpVHOiXsorP/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Here’s an Instagram post</a> showcasing our <a href="https://wearepf.com/how-to-social-media-guides/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">how-to social media guides for LinkedIn, Twitter, Instagram and Facebook</a>.</li>
</ul>
Repurposing content is the relief you need from the time spent creating content. If you have a valuable piece of content on your hands, maximise your time and your reach by sharing it every possible way you can. If you want to get help with this, <a href="https://wearepf.com/diagnostic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fill in our discovery form</a> and chat to one of our team to see how you can repurpose an existing piece of content you’re proud of.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>16407</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2023-05-19 09:15:48]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2023-05-19 09:15:48]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2023-05-19 09:15:48]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2023-05-19 09:15:48]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[repurpose-content-get-most-value]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="all"><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blogging"><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="content"><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="content"><![CDATA[Content]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="content-marketing"><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="content-plan"><![CDATA[content plan]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="pf-marketing-tips"><![CDATA[PF Marketing Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="social-media"><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="social-media"><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="social-media-for-accountants"><![CDATA[social media for accountants]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="video-content"><![CDATA[video content]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="video-marketing"><![CDATA[video marketing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[32]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_610f8bd31ede0247031d38a4ace592c1]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[add_custom_body_class]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dfiFeatured]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[500]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_estimated-reading-time-minutes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[8]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_wordproof_timestamp]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[16408]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_opengraph-image]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Repurposing-content-blog-header-image-1024x679.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_opengraph-image-id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[16408]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[repurpose existing content]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Repurpose existing content to get the most value %%page%% %%sep%% %%sitename%%]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[A way to save all that time and energy creating original content takes, you can repurpose existing content and share it in lots of different formats.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[71]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2023-05-18]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[3 ways to make your firm’s content more inclusive]]></title>
		<link>https://wearepf.com/make-firms-content-more-inclusive/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 08:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camilla Duggan]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wearepf.com/?p=16424</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<b><img class="aligncenter wp-image-16425 size-full" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/3-ways-make-content-more-inclusive-scaled.jpeg" alt="" width="2560" height="1699" /></b>
<h2><b>It’s not a woke thing. It’s a welcome-all-folk thing.</b></h2>
This blog is not about the greater work of workplace equity and diversity.

<a href="https://wearepf.com/people/stephanie-gonzalez/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stephi</a>, one of our Client Marketing Managers, has already written an excellent resource on how to <a href="https://wearepf.com/how-intentionally-build-multicultural-team-accounting-firm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">build a multicultural team within your accounting firm</a>. And you can apply each of the 3 actionable tips in this blog to your marketing for hiring and careers.

This is about taking small steps to create content that <em>everyone</em> in your audience can consume, understand and relate to.

Why wouldn’t we want to open more doors to our services and support?
<h2>Inclusivity is not about widening your audience - it’s about welcoming everyone within it</h2>
Great marketing is rooted in the experiences, problems and needs of your audience.

When the net is cast really wide, those experiences, problems and needs become so varied and it’s hard to pinpoint the common denominators. As a result your content becomes more generalised and less effective.

The idea is to catch the attention of your very ideal clients (make them say “that’s so me!”) and focus all your messaging on them.

<strong>When we talk about making your content more inclusive, we mean more inclusive within your defined ideal audience.</strong>

For example:
<ul>
 	<li><em>If you’re an accounting firm that specialises in helping parents in business, is there an opportunity to represent different parental setups in your imagery?</em></li>
 	<li><em>If you’re best at helping young creative entrepreneurs, could you make it so that all people within that group have equal access to your content?</em></li>
</ul>
You don’t need to pivot off-brand suddenly and be everything to everyone. You can be authentically you and make more inclusive choices.
<h2>Three ways your content can show up for more people: make it reflective, accessible and representative</h2>
&nbsp;
<h2>1. Make it more reflective</h2>
<ul>
 	<li><strong>Check your stock imagery:</strong> your opportunity to feature images of people of different ages, genders, ethnicities, faiths, abilities, sexualities, cultural backgrounds.</li>
</ul>
<strong>Here are some examples to explore (but there are lots more out there!):</strong>

<a href="https://nappy.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Beautiful photos of Black and Brown people from Nappy</a>
<a href="https://www.gettyimages.ca/photos/67percentcollection" target="_blank" rel="noopener">All body shapes and sizes from Getty</a>
<a href="https://genderspectrum.vice.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The gender spectrum collection from Vice</a>
<a href="https://www.stocksy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Progressive stock imagery from Stocksy</a>
<a href="https://www.theunmistakables.com/despora" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Despora collection from The Unmistakeables</a>
<a href="http://The Disabled and Here collection" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Disabled and Here collection</a>
<a href="https://ageingbetter.resourcespace.com/pages/home.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Age positive image library</a>
<a href="https://jopwell.pixieset.com/jopwell_latinxcollection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Latinx photo collection from Jopwell</a>

<strong>Look for areas where you can make an inclusive switch:</strong>

<em>Work with tech companies but only ever show stock images of men? &gt; Check out this <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/wocintechchat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">women in tech collection from Flickr.</a></em>

<em>Work with parents in business but only featuring white families? &gt; Check out this <a href="https://www.pexels.com/search/diverse%20family/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">diverse family collection on Pexel.</a></em>

<em>Got a brand that features a lot of illustration? Check out some more inclusive libraries, such as:</em>

<a href="https://www.openpeeps.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open peeps hand drawn illustrations library</a>
<a href="https://www.blackillustrations.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Black illustrations.com</a>
<ul>
 	<li><strong>Check your language:</strong> How might language have evolved or progressed? Spot check yourself for stereotypes and seek opportunities to welcome rather than alienate.</li>
</ul>
-Parents <strong>might not be</strong> ‘mum and dad’

- A couple <strong>might not be</strong> a husband &amp; wife

- Re-evaluate where you might be using problematic language casually, like describing a meticulous organisation of spreadsheets as ‘OCD’.

- How often are you reverting to stereotypes in stories or analogies?

- Consider what's 'obvious'! What's obvious to you might not be obvious to everyone

<em>*Accounting has its own stereotype! Erin, one of PF’s content writers, did a deep dive into the boring accounting stereotype in a recent blog. <a href="https://wearepf.com/stuffy-accountant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">It’s time to unpack the stuffy accountant stereotype. Do you still believe in it?</a></em>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16426 size-full" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/UN-women-gender-language-graphic.png" alt="" width="325" height="325" />

Image Source: <a href="https://www.unwomen.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UN Women</a>
<h2>2. Make it more accessible</h2>
<ul>
 	<li>
<h4>Write Alt Text to describe images for audio-only users</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Alternative (Alt) Text describes the content of an image you share online (on your website, in blogs, on social media). As well as being indexed by search engines, this text is read aloud by screen readers. </span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">Social platforms (like LinkedIn) make this really easy. You’re prompted to add Alt Text whenever you share a photo.</span>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16427 size-full" src="https://wearepf.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Alt-text-example-graphic.png" alt="" width="484" height="414" />

&nbsp;

<strong>Adding alt text to your website images requires a little adventure into the backend of your website. </strong>

If you are using WordPress or a content management system like Squarespace, you will find an option to add a title, caption, and alternative text when you upload an image.
<ul>
 	<li>
<h4><strong>Create captions on videos for visual-only users</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
Most video messaging software and social media platforms have an in-built caption service available. This not only enables people who are Deaf or hard-of-hearing to consume your content, it’s great for non-native speakers too.
<h3><strong>Want to go further?</strong></h3>
<h4>This blog post is focused on easy actionable steps you can take yourself. But you could consult a web developer (<a href="https://wearepf.com/people/melissa-gilbert/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">meet Mel</a>) if you want to optimise your whole website for accessibility. This might include looking at the navigation and HTML setup of your pages.</h4>
*Note: Do think carefully and consciously about how often you change your site navigation. Lots of regular BIG changes can cause trouble for people who rely on audio directions, because they will need to relearn the navigation.
<h2>3. Make it more representative</h2>
<ul>
 	<li>
<h4><strong>Represent and celebrate the clients you already serve</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
For Revel CPA, equity and representation matters. They're all about lifting up their clients, and their social feed really shows it.
<blockquote class="instagram-media" style="background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/Crg60mzBb0h/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14">
<div style="padding: 16px;">

&nbsp;
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;"></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style="color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style="width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>
&nbsp;
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;"><a style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Crg60mzBb0h/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A post shared by Revel CPA | The Creatives’ CPA (@revelcpa)</a></p>

</div></blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" style="background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CspC1YhpP5x/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14">
<div style="padding: 16px;">

&nbsp;
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;"></div>
<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style="color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;">View this post on Instagram</div>
</div>
<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);"></div>
</div>
<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style="width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>
<div style="width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>
<div style="background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>
&nbsp;
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;"><a style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CspC1YhpP5x/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A post shared by Revel CPA | The Creatives’ CPA (@revelcpa)</a></p>

</div></blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

Like Revel, you can make a conscious effort to showcase your clients in your communications. This <em>shows</em> rather than tells people the wide range of people you support.
<ul>
 	<li>Get images of real clients on your website</li>
 	<li>Feature clients stories on your blog and on social media</li>
 	<li>Create posts showing appreciation and understanding for clients’ experiences, celebratory days, hardships etc.</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;
<ul>
 	<li>
<h4><strong>Get to know your ideal client</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;

Remember, this isn’t about widening your audience, it's about considering all the different people and perspectives <em>within</em> your ideal audience.

Ask:
<ul>
 	<li><em>Who is your audience made up of?</em></li>
 	<li><em>What are their backgrounds and life experiences/perspectives?</em></li>
 	<li><em>What’s important to them, what do they value?</em></li>
 	<li><em>What might they come to your content hoping for or expecting?</em></li>
 	<li><em>Who is consuming your content regularly? Who might not be and why?</em></li>
</ul>
These questions require a deep dive: into your observations as a firm owner (and those of your team) but also into the data - from analytics, website forms, sales interactions. This is just one part of what we cover in <a href="https://wearepf.com/foundations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Foundations sessions</a> with clients. And it’s the reason why ‘Audience’ is session one for our <a href="https://wearepf.com/accelerator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Accelerator coaching group.</a>

Once we know the answers to these questions, we can begin to create content that feels representative of reality, rather than only our assumptions or biases.

For example, you might stop sending that “Happy Easter” email out if you realise a large percentage of your email list doesn’t celebrate Easter. You might rethink the next case study you publish when you know there’s a story that might resonate more intimately with your viewers.
<h2>Keep listening, learning and growing in your content creation</h2>
We can all make a conscious effort to share content online that is accessible to, and representative of, all people within our audience.

Representation matters to our prospects and customers. Inclusive content shows our audience that <strong>we see all of them.</strong>

I’ll leave you with three tips we can all take into our content creation:
<ul>
 	<li><strong>Question everything</strong> - get comfortable with the uncomfortableness of your own blind spots and biases.</li>
 	<li><strong>Observe your audience!</strong> Lean into curiosity. Ask your clients and followers questions. Don’t rely solely on assumptions, dig into the data.</li>
 	<li><strong>Welcome feedback</strong> - If you want to improve, listen actively to your community and use feedback as an opportunity to grow.</li>
</ul>
If you want someone to review your content with a fresh perspective, we have strategists, designers, writers and developers on hand to help. Fill our <a href="https://wearepf.com/discovery/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">discovery form</a> and tell us where you might need in your content creation journey.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>16424</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2023-06-02 08:31:01]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2023-06-02 08:31:01]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2023-06-02 15:30:29]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2023-06-02 15:30:29]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[make-firms-content-more-inclusive]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="accessible"><![CDATA[accessible]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="audience"><![CDATA[Audience]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="blogging"><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="content"><![CDATA[Content]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="content"><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="content-marketing"><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="diversity"><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="equity"><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="helping"><![CDATA[Helping]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ideal-audience"><![CDATA[ideal audience]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="inclusive"><![CDATA[inclusive]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="messaging"><![CDATA[messaging]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="pf-marketing-tips"><![CDATA[PF Marketing Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="recommendations"><![CDATA[Recommendations]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="reflective"><![CDATA[reflective]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="representative"><![CDATA[representative]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="storytelling"><![CDATA[Storytelling]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="values"><![CDATA[Values]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[51]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[add_custom_body_class]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dfiFeatured]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[45]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[90]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_estimated-reading-time-minutes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_wordproof_timestamp]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[16425]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[inclusive content]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[This blog is about taking small steps to create inclusive content that everyone in your audience can consume, understand and relate to.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[71]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>
	